Curriculum Vita

Mahmoud Al-Shawish

Software Engineer

United Arab Emirates Tel: +971 50 363 4715

Email: mhmoodsh1996@gmail.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-alshawish-917091171/

Objective

I'm a Fresh Graduate with a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

Eager for an opportunity to utilize my special set of skills, who doesn't shy away from Challenges, experienced in working under Pressure, and genuinely interested in an opportunity to work with an organization like yours.

Work Experience

PocketDoc (Graduation project)

Internship

Jan. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Description: The idea of this application is to ease the communication between the patient and his/her doctor and to decrease the need for going to the doctor's clinic.

- Gathered the Requirements for the application.
- Coordinated and managed team members tasks and activities.
- Creatively Designed the application interface and inner dynamics.
- Made the scenarios about how the application will function.
- Designed flow charts for sequence events.
- Designed the logo for the application.
- Implemented the application for the patient's side.
- Implemented the chat screen between the patient and the doctor.
- Tested the application's functional and non-functional requirements.
- Fixed the bugs and issues in the application.
- Maintained the application for future updates.

Photographer

Freelance

Jan. 2018 - Present

- Sharpening my skills in photoshop for designing web pages.
- Enhancing my illustration skills to make icons and logos for my applications.
- Editing photos using adobe photoshop, lightroom and illustrator.
- Training beginner photographers.
- Retouch model portraits.
- Video editing using Adobe Premiere.
- Analyzing videos and reediting them.
- Fixing sounds in videos and adding effects.
- My portfolio: https://www.instagram.com/mahmoud captures/

VR Zone-jo

Assist Manager & Game Master

June 2019 – Feb. 2021

- Fixed computer issues.
- Fixed VR issues.
- Fixed VR system crashes.
- Tested applications.
- Tested purchased games.
- Tested VR hardware.
- Facilitated the Sales operation.
- Assembling Omni treadmills and VR kits in universities for our clients.

Go Sport

Salesman

Aug. 2016 - June 2017

- Help customers and making good offers.
- Selling in wholesale and retail.
- Used to sell in wholesale and retail.



Technical Skills

- Advanced skills in Web development in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Nodejs, and Reactjs using Atom IDE.
- Advanced skills in Mobile development using Flutter framework and Google Firebase in Visual Studio IDE to design and build Android mobile applications.
- Advanced skills knowledge in using SQL commands.
- Advanced skills at using Adobe Photoshop to design web pages and user interface.
- Advanced skills at using Adobe Illustrator to make logos, icons, and illustrations to use them in my Web development and Mobile Applications.
- Advanced knowledge in React Native.
- Advanced knowledge in programing in Python.

Education & Certificates

- University of Petra Bachelor's degree in Software engineering 2017 – 2021.
- Flutter & Dart The Complete Guide Udemy / 2021.
- React Native The Practical Guide Udemy / 2021.
- Complete Python Bootcamp from Zero to Hero Udemy / 2021.
- Adobe Photoshop CC Advanced Training Course Udemy / 2021.
- Master The Coding Interview Data Structure & Algorithms -Udemy / 2021.
- Adobe Illustrator CC Essentials Training Course Udemy / 2021.
- Web Development The complete guide Udemy / 2021.

Key Skills & Characteristics

- Fluent in Arabic and English.
- Excellent communication skills.
- Advanced Knowledge of Windows and Microsoft Suite.
- Creative and Imaginative.
- Can work under pressure.
- Constant desire to develop and sharpen my skills and capabilities.
- Research methodology.
- Service quality.
- Willing to relocate where needed.
- Valid driving license.